{
    "quiz1":[
        {
            "num" : 1,
            "type" : "multiple_choice" ,
            "question" : "Which is the correct way to print \"Hello World\" in Java?",
            "A" : "print(\"Hello World\");",
            "B" : "Console.WriteLine(\"Hello World\");",
            "C" : "System.out.println(\"Hello World\");",
            "answer" : "C",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is C.  A & B are written in different programming languages."
        },

        {
            "num" : 2,
            "type" : "true_false",
            "question" : "Java is short for JavaScript.",
            "T" : "True",
            "F" : "False",
            "answer" : "False",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is false. JavaScript is a different programming language than Java."
        },

        {
            "num" : 3,
            "type" : "short_answer",
            "question" : "Declare a variable, x, of type Integer with the value 4 in Java.",
            "answer" : "int x = 4;",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is: int x = 4;"
            
        },

        {
            "num" : 4,
            "type" : "true_false",
            "question" : "public static void setInt(int i){}; is a method that returns an integer",
            "T" : "True",
            "F" : "False",
            "answer" : "False",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is false. Void methods do not have a return type."
        },

        {
            "num" : 5,
            "type" : "multiple_choice" ,
            "question" : "Which data type is used to create a variable that stores text?",
            "A" : "String",
            "B" : "Integer",
            "C" : "Boolean",
            "answer" : "A",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is A. Integers store numbers and Booleans store True/False values."
        },

        {
            "num" : 6,
            "type" : "short_answer",
            "question" : "How is \"not equal to\" expressed in java?",
            "answer" : "!=",
            "explanation" : "The correct way to exparess \"not equal to\" in java is !="              
        },

        {
            "num" : 7,
            "type" : "true_false",
            "question" : "Linked lists contain nodes.",
            "T" : "True",
            "F" : "False",
            "answer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is True.  Linked lists contain nodes which have a data field as well as a next field."
        },

        {
            "num" : 8,
            "type" : "multiple_choice" ,
            "question" : "What is the correct Big O Notation for linear time?",
            "A" : "O(1)",
            "B" : "O(n)",
            "C" : "O(n^2)",
            "answer" : "B",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is B. O(1) is constant time, O(n^2) is quadratic time."
        },

        {
            "num" : 9,
            "type" : "multiple_choice" ,
            "question" : "Which is the correct answer to declare an String array named \"stringArray\" with a length of 10 in Java?",
            "A" : "Array(String) stringArray = new Array(10);",
            "B" : "String[10] stringArray = new String[];",
            "C" : "String[] stringArray = new String[10];",
            "answer" : "C",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is C."
        },

        {
            "num" : 10,
            "type" : "true_false",
            "question" : "Sets allow duplicate elements.",
            "T" : "True",
            "F" : "False",
            "answer" : "False",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is False.  Sets do not allow duplicate elements."
        },

        {
            "num" : 11,
            "type" : "short_answer",
            "question" : "The last node in a signly linked list will point to: ",
            "answer" : "null",
            "explanation" : "The last item in a singly linked list will point to null."
        },

        {
            "num" : 12,
            "type" : "short_answer",
            "question" : "What is the output of the following Java code: System.out.println(\"2^(2+1)\");",
            "answer" : "2^(2+1)",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is 2^(2+1).  Because the equation is in double quotes it will print the equation instead of solving it."
        },

        {
            "num" : 13,
            "type" : "true_false",
            "question" : "HTML stands for Hypertext Markup Language.",
            "T" : "True",
            "F" : "False",
            "answer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is True."
        },

        {
            "num" : 14,
            "type" : "multiple_choice" ,
            "question" : "A linked list is empty if the head node equals:",
            "A" : "null",
            "B" : "0",
            "C" : "empty",
            "answer" : "A",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is A, a linked list is empty when the head node has a value of null."
        },

        {
            "num" : 15,
            "type" : "short_answer",
            "question" : "What is the output of the following Java code: System.out.println(10%2);",
            "answer" : "0",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is 0.  The remainder of 10 / 2 is 0."
        },

        {
            "num" : 16,
            "type" : "multiple_choice" ,
            "question" : "The first element in array \"x\" is expressed as: ",
            "A" : "x[1]",
            "B" : "x[0]",
            "C" : "x.firstElement",
            "answer" : "B",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is B.  0 is the first index of an array."
        }
    ],

    "quiz2" :[
        {
            "num" : 1,
            "type" : "short_answer",
            "question" : "Declare a String, \"name\", that holds the name Bob in Java.",
            "answer" : "String name = \"Bob\";",
            "explanation" : "The correct syntax is: String name = \"Bob\";"
        },

        {
            "num" : 2,
            "type" : "true_false",
            "question" : "\"public static void main(String[] args){}\" declares a main method in Java",
            "T" : "True",
            "F" : "False",
            "answer" : "True",
            "explanation" : "The correct answer is True."

        }
    ]
  }
